Parth Chawla

Davis, California 95616 (530) 760-8670 chawla@ucdavis.edu www.linkedin.com/in/parthchawla https://github.com/parthchawla

Agricultural & Resource Economics Ph.D. student with 2 years of experience in policy research, data and statistical analysis, and project management. Interested in exploring the use of technology for solving policy-related problems.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

• Python

SQL & MySQL

Stata

• AWS EC2 & RDS

• Data visualization

• Web scraping

Statistical analysis & modelling

• Data pipelining

• Unix shell scripting

EDUCATION

Ph.D. in Agricultural & Resource Economics – University of California, Davis; GPA: 3.7/4

2021 -

M.Sc. in Economics – Trinity College Dublin

2018 - 2019

B.Sc. in Physics – Royal Holloway, University of London

2014 - 2017

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Research Associate

Evidence for Policy Design (EPoD at Harvard Kennedy School) – Delhi, India

June 2019 – May 2021

- Executed two large scale research projects studying the impact of technological solutions on bureaucratic efficiency in rural India in collaboration with development economists from Yale University and the University of Michigan.
- Lead field-based and data operations teams consisting of field managers, field-based surveyors and data entry
 operators.
- Liaised with government officials across many levels in India and used their feedback to align project goals.
- Created Python data pipelines, scraped large datasets from the web/APIs, used Amazon Web Services for storing data and automating code.
- Prepared data visualizations and performed econometric analysis using Stata for presenting findings.
- Conducted qualitative and quantitative research, designed survey questionnaires, ran pilot exercises and refined the study design.

Economics Intern

Koan Advisory - Delhi, India

May - June 2018

Research Engineer - Intern

Vzzual Ltd – Guildford, United Kingdom

June – August 2016

AWARDS AND FELLOWSHIPS

- UC Davis Provost's Fellowship: \$58,302
- Royal Holloway Passport Award
- Royal Holloway International Excellence Scholarship: £10,000

OTHER EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant (Math & Statistics for Economics) Trinity College Dublin – Dublin, Ireland

September 2018 – May 2019

Teaching Fellow (Math Foundation Course) Ashoka University – Sonipat, India

January – May 2018